

# Anuraj Mohan

Academician . Researcher

- Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering
- NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad
- Kerala, India 678008

## **Education**

**Doctor of Philosophy** 

#### Area : Network Representation Learning

Dept. of Computer Applications

Cochin University of Science and Technology

2017 - 2022

#### Master of Engineering

# Computer Science and Engineering

Anna University, Chennai

2013 - 2015

#### **Bachelor of Technology**

# Computer Science and Engineering

Cochin University of Science and Technology

2001 - 2005

### **Biography**

Dr. Anuraj Mohan obtained the B.Tech Degree in Computer Science and Engineering from Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin and the Master Degree in Computer Science and Engineering from Anna University, Chennai. He received the Ph.D. degree in the area of network representation learning under the Faculty of Technology, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin. He has more than 16 years of experience as Assistant Professor at Department of Computer Science and Engineering, NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad. He has published various research articles in SCI indexed journals of reputed publishers like Elsevier and Springer. His broad areas of interest include machine learning, text and social network mining, and big data analytics.

## Work Experience

# Assistant Professor | Department of Computer Science and Engineering

06/02/2006 - today

NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad

A government aided institution affiliated to APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University, Kerala

### Research Interests

- Geometric Deep Learning
- Social Network Mining
- Big Data Analytics

### **Refereed Journal Publications**

- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2022), Representation learning for temporal networks using temporal random walk and deep autoencoder, *Discrete Applied Mathematics(SCI, IF 1.1)*, *Elsevier*. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dam.2022.01.017
- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2021), Temporal network embedding using graph attention network, Complex and Intelligent Systems(SCIE, IF 3.7), Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40747-021-00332-x
- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2020), Link prediction in dynamic networks using time-aware network embedding and time series forecasting, *Journal of Am*bient Intelligence and Humanized Computing(SCIE, IF 4.5), Springer, Vol 12, pp. 1981–1993.
- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2019), Network representation learning: models, methods and applications, SN Applied Sciences(ESCI), Springer, Vol 1, pp. 1-23.
- Anuraj Mohan, R Venkatesan and K. V. Pramod (2017), A scalable method for link prediction in large real world networks, *Journal of Parallel and Distributed* Computing(SCI, IF 2.2), Elsevier, Vol 109, pp. 89-101.
- Nisha C C and Anuraj Mohan (2018), A social recommender system using deep architecture and network embedding, Applied Intelligence(SCI, IF 3.3), Springer, Vol 49, pp. 1937-1953.
- Aswathy Divakaran and **Anuraj Mohan** (2019), Temporal Link Prediction: A Survey, *New Generation Computing(SCIE, IF 0.8), Springer*, Vol 38, pp. 213-258.

### **Contact**

- Sarangi
  - Akathethara, Palakkad 678008
- $\Box$  +91 9496353749
- anurajmohan@gmail.com
- anurajmohan@nssce.ac.in

### **SKills**

Python, Scikit-Learn, NetworkX, Keras, Pytorch, Hadoop, Spark, SQL

# **Subject Expertise**

Theory of Computation, Data Structures, Operating Systems, Python Programming, Database Systems, Machine Learning, Information Retrieval.

### **Recent Activities**

- Reviewer for IEEE Transactions on Computational Social Systems
- Reviewer for New Generation Computing, Springer
- Reviewer for Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing, Springer
- Invited Talk on 'Network Embedding' for National Workshop on Graphs Complex Networks at CUSAT, Cochin

### Web Links

- Google Scholar : https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=PwHP6YoAAAAJhl=en
- ORCHID : https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1044-9368
- ResearchGate: https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Anuraj-Mohan-2
- Publons: https://publons.com/researcher/4731079/anuraj-mohan/
- Webpage : https://anurajmohan.in/

	Palakkad,	14th	March	2022
--	-----------	------	-------	------